어지러운 전국 시대.
It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
무사시 등장이오!
Musashi is here-dasu!
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
A man always dreams of the day
제일 강해질 날을
in the center of the world to become
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
AH! AH! the strongest
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
모험의 길의 막을 연다
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes a life dazzle
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
내일은 빛난다
Tomorrow will be glorious
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes a life dazzle
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Fight the utmost with the stillness
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
His eyes shined! Musashi!!
지팡구 제일의 무예가를 꿈꾸며 여행을 떠난 무사시는 칼 장인 코테츠에게 제자임을 보이고
[?] Dreaming for the number one Martial Artist of Jipangu State, Musashi showed Kotetsu, the master sword craftsman, that he is a pupil.
결국엔 명검을 손에 넣게 되었다.
Finally he managed to get those master's swords.
대만족, 기분은 지팡구 제일이었지만, 과연 앞길에서 기다리는 것은 바람인가 폭풍인가?
He was very satisfied! He felt like he already became the number one of Jipangu,
but what will be waiting in front of him? Wind or storm?
나는 스승이오
훌륭하오!
I am a Master
Excellent!
배 갑니다!
Ship is about to depart!
어이! 배 갑니다!
Repeat! Shop is about to depart!
기다리시오!
Wait!
잠시 기다리시오!
Just a moment!
나도 타겠소!
I'll ride too-dasu!
세이프이오!
Safe-dasu!
여하튼 무예를 단련하고 있으니 이쯤이야!
Anyway, since I'm training martial arts, so this is nothing!
흥! 꼴사나워라.
Hmph! How unsightly.
뭐라?
What?!
어? 저건 코지로!
Huh? You are Kojirō!
흥, 뭐가 무예의 단련이냐? 집오리가 춤추는 것만 같은 흉한 꼴을 하고!
You call that training for martial arts? You look very unsightly, like a dancing house duck!
집오리가 춤춘다?
Dancing house duck?
맞는 말이군!
That's right!
네이놈, 잘도 나를 모욕했겠소!
How dare you bastard insult me-dasu!
용서할 수 없소! 자, 순순히 승부를 보시오!
Unforgivable-dasu! Tamely do a fair match with me-dasu!
오, 뭔가 칼 같아 보이는 것을 손에 넣은 모양이구나.
Oh, I see you got something that looks like a sword.
때와 장소를 가리지 못하고 칼을 뽑는 것은 아직 수련이 부족하구나!
Also I see your training wasn't enough to identify where to pull your sword out and where not to!
다른 승객 여러분에게 끼치는 폐는 생각하지 못하다니, 분수를 몰라도 유분수지!
Can't you think about the troble to other passengers? Be polite to other people even if you don't know about yourself!
근데 그 칼, 설마 장난감 아니냐?
But I wonder... isn't that sword a toy?
무, 무슨! 이건 그 유명한 칼 장인, 코테츠가 만든 명검이오!
N- no way! This is the excellent sword made by Kotetsu, the famous sword craftsman-dasu!
승부를 보면 날카로움을 볼 수 있을 것이오!
By having a match, you will see its sharpness-dasu!
칼을 꺼내시오, 코지로!
Pull your sword out, Kojirō!
답이 없는 녀석이군.
What a hopeless guy.
좋다, 저긴 어떠냐.
Okay then. Let's have a match on there.
좋소!
Agreed!
자, 코지로! 오늘로 결판을 내겠소!
Now, Kojirō! I'll finish this as of today-dasu!
어?
Huh?
너같은 멧돼지같은 꼬마하고 놀고 있을 여유 따위 없다는 걸 잊어먹고 있었다!
I forgot that I had no time to play with a baby wild boar like you!
뭐, 뭐시라?
What did you say-dasu?!
코지로! 비겁하오! 사내답지 않소! 무예가도 아니오!
Kojirō, you're cowardly-dasu! You're not a man-dasu! You're not even a Martial Artist-dasu!
(무수승류: 無手勝流, 무테카츠류. 싸우지 않고 이김)
이건 머리를 쓰는 고도 전술, 무수승류다!
(Mutekatsu-ryu: 無手勝流. Winning without fighting)
This is a intense tactic that uses brain, Mutekatsu-ryu!
자신의 성격을 반성해라! 바보 놈!
Have a time examining yourself! Idiot!
시끄럽소! 닥치시오! 닥치시오!
You're noisy-dasu! Shut up! Shut up-dasu!
네이놈, 코지로! 비겁한 자식!
Damn you, Kojirō! You cowardly bastard!
아, 비참하오...
I feel so miserable-dasu...
이 분함, 절대 잊지 않겠소!
I will never forget this bitterness-dasu!
코지로 놈! 다시 만나면 10등분으로 베어 주겠소!
Damn that Kojirō! If we meet again, I'll cut you into pieces-dasu!
역시 명검!
Expected from this sword!
이야, 훌륭하오! 대단한 검술. 진정으로 감탄했습니다.
That's splendid! Excellent swordsmanship. I am genuinely struck with admiration.
아니, 그 정도는 아니오.
I'm not on the level of that-dasu.
이야, 거두는 방법도 또 어깨에 꼭 맞고...
Your way of taking sword in is just right too...
저는 코헤이라고 하는 갓 시작한 무예가이지만 부디 스승님의의 제자가 되고 싶습니다.
I am a new Martial Artist named Kohei, and I want to be a pupil of yours.
제자? 스승, 나 말이오?
Pupil? With me as a master-dasu?
예, 오늘 지금 당장 스승님이라고 부르겠습니다.
Right. I will start calling you as master from now on.
그, 그래도, 나, 아니, 소생은 저, 수련, 아니, 아니, 기술을 쌓는...
Bu- but, I, yet, no, I... train... no, gaining techniques...
겸손하신 모습이 또 한층 우아하게 보이십니다. 존경합니다.
Your modestly makes you even more elegant. I respect you.
그럼 받아들이겠소.
Then I'll accept-dasu.
자, 자, 저기에 찻집이 보입니다. 단고라도 드실 동안 대선생의 말씀을 생각하고 싶습니다.
I see a tea house over there. I want to think about your teachings while you have some dangos.
단고?!
Dango?!
어, 어쩔 수가 없소. 단고에는 눈이 돌아, 아니아니, 네 열의에 눈이 돌았으니 이야기를 하겠소.
I can't refuse that-dasu. I have no eyes for dango, no, for your enthusiasm, so I'll talk with you-dasu.
이야, 역시 대선생! 단고를 먹는 방법도 참으로 사내답게 호쾌하시군요.
That's my master! The way you eat dangos is so manly and superb.
응, 무예가라면 먹을 때에도 사양하면 안 되오.
Right, if you are a swordsman, even when you eat, you must not be modest.
그렇군요. 훌륭한 마음으로...
I see. With a excellent spirit...
저, 제 몫도 원하신다면... 드세요.
If you want mine too, you can have them.
뭔가, 먹을 것을 남겨서는 일류의 무예가가 되지 못하오!
If you leave your food, you won't become a first-class Martial Artist-dasu!
이야! 배불렀소.
I feel so full.
주인장! 얼마이오?
Host! How much are they-dasu?
네, 100문입니다.
They are 100 mons.
100문?!
100 mons?!
그, 그런 돈은 어디에도 없소...
I have no money for that-dasu...
아, 아니, 스승님, 이런 일은 제자인 제게 맡겨 주세요.
No, master. Leave such things to me, your pupil-dasu.
주인장, 잘 먹었소. 여기 받으세요.
The food was excellent today. Here you go.
예, 감사합니다.
Thank you.
제자란 것은 편리한 것이오...
A pupil is convenient-dasu...
제자하하하...
Pupilehehehehehe...
여기서부터 쿠마노미로
Kumanomiro from here
지팡구 무예 대회인가.
Jipangu Martial Arts Competition?
예. 에도토피아의 쇼군 이에야스 공이 주최하는 지팡구 제일의 무예 대회로 매년 연말에 열립니다.
Yes. It is the martial arts competition of Jipangu at the end of every year sponsored by Ieyasu, the Shogun of Edotopia.
거기서 우승하면?
What happens if I win?
물론! 지팡구 제일의 무예가로.
Of course you become the number one Martial Artist of Jipangu.
스승님 정도의 실력이라면 우승할 것이 틀림없습니다.
With your level of technique, you definitely are going to win.
무, 물론이오! 나는 지금부터 에도토피아를 향하겠소.
O- of course-dasu! From now on, I am heading to Edotopia-dasu.
함께 가 드리겠습니다.
I will go with you.
이상하오. 점점 산속에 들어가는 것 같소.
Something's not right-dasu. I think we're going inside to a mountain-dasu.
어? 저기에 간판이 보입니다.
Huh? I see a sign there.
무단 출입 금지. 금령을 어긴 자의 목숨은 보장할 수 없음.
Do not enter. The life of violators is not guaranteed.
호조인
Hozoin
호조인.
Hozoin.
호조인? 이상한 이름이오.
Hozoin? What a weird name-dasu.
스승님, 제가 들은 바가 있습니다.
Master. I've heard about them.
뭐래도 중 주제에 경은 제쳐두고, 묘한 창을 쓰는 무서운 놈이라 들었습니다.
He is a monk, but he puts the sutras away, and he is told to be using a weird spear.
중이 무예를 하오?
A monk is into martial arts-dasu?!
그뿐만이 아니라, 많은 제자를 모아 전쟁을 일으키고, 나라를 쓰러뜨리겠다고 계획한다고 하는 소문.
That's not all. It is told that he's gathering lots of pupils to start a war and planning to take down the country.
내 마을에 타쿠안 스님이라면 네이놈! 하고 화낼 소리이오.
Takuan, a monk in my village, would shout YOU BRAT!-dasu.
대스승님의 힘으로 세상을 위해, 사람을 위해 응징해 주십시오!
With the master's power, please punish them for the people and for the world!
말할 필요도 없소. 이런 간판 따위 부수겠소!
No need to say-dasu. I will destroy such sign-dasu!
어라?
Huh?
뭣이오?
What is it?
너냐! 호조인 대스승님께 시비를 거는 자는!
Is it you? Did you asked for a fight to master Hozoin?
여보시오. 이 자는 내 제자이오.
Hey. This person is my pupil-dasu.
이야기라면 나, 아니, 소생에가 하시오.
If you have something to say, do it to me-dasu.
뭐냐, 네가? 농담은 그만 하고 먼저 손을 붙이고 사과해라!
What, you are? Stop with that joke and beg for pardon on your knees!
농담 아니오! 나는 잘난 척하는 놈에게 머리를 숙이는 것과 금가는 것과 민달팽이가 정말 싫소!
I'm not joking-dasu. I hate cracks, snails, and begging to a braggart-dasu!
애송이라 생각했지만 순순히 굴지 못할망정 싸움을 걸다니!
You're not a simple brat, to ask for a fight instead of being obedient!
아파도 울지 마라!
Don't cry even if it hurts!
스승님!
Master!
나에게 맡기시오!
Leave it to me!
이런 패거리, 바로 처리해 주겠소!
I will take care of this bunch-dasu!
좋소.
Then.
네이놈, 말 그만두지 못할까!
You brat, shut your mouth!
(아라기리: 粗切り. 거칠게 대충대충 자름)
(Aragiri: 粗切り. rogh cut)
상관없다! 호조인 류 아라기리를 보여주겠다!
It doesn't matter now! I'll show you the Aragiri in Hozoin flavor!
이 정도쯤이야! 내가 한 수 가르쳐 주겠소!
This is nothing! I'll teach you something instead-dasu!
으윽! 당했다!
I am done for!
오버하긴! 그냥 칼등일 뿐이오!
Don't overact! It's just the back side of sword-dasu!
나, 무익한 일은 하지 않기로 했소!
I will not do something useless-dasu!
꼬맹이 앞에서 허둥대지 마라! 둘러싸 두들겨 죽여라!
Don't be flustered in front of a brat! Surrond him and beat him to death!
무슨. 지팡구 제일의 무예가를 꿈꾸는 무사시 님이오. 간단히 당하지 않소!
I am Musashi, who dreams to be the number one Martial Artist of Jipangu-dasu. I won't be down so easily-dasu!
무사시 스승님!
Master Musashi!
나에게서 떨어지지 마시오!
Don't get away from me-dasu!
네! 스승님!
Right! Master!
꽤 하는가 보오, 코헤이 씨!
You do well, Mr. Kohei!
아니, 우연입니다.
No, this was by chance.
스승님을 따라했을 뿐입니다.
I was just imitating you.
에이, 귀찮다! 진짜 창으로 찍소리 못하게 끝내버려라!
They're being annoying! Finish them with real spears to make them shut up!
네이놈!
You bastards!
스승님! 안 됩니다! 여긴 달아나야 합니다!
No, master! We have to run away from here!
그, 그런 말을 하면 곤란하오! 우리 둘은 여럿에게 당하는 것 따위 비겁은 용서할 수 없소!
No- nonsense-dasu! We cannot forgive a cowardliness of being attacked by many people-dasu!
스승님! 괜찮습니까?
Master! Are you alright?!
무슨. 고향 미야모토 마을에서는 산이나 숲에서 칼싸움을 매일같이 해 왔으니까!
No problem. I've been playing using swords even when I was in my home town Miyamoto village!
칼싸움이라니 아주 웃기는구나!
Sword play is something to laugh about!
그것도 수련의 하나이오! 명확하게 보여주겠쇼!
It is definitely a training-dasu! I'll show you clearly-dasu!
잡아라!
Don't let them run away!
대단해요, 무사시 스승님!
Awesome, master Musashi!
이런 건 쉽소!
This is nothing!
무사시 스승님!
Master Musashi!
너무 휩쓸렸나...
Maybe I pushed him too much...
여긴 어떤 짐승도 살아서 나갈 수 없는 자연의 무덤. 수고를 줄였군.
You are now in the grave of nature that nobody can escape alive. One less troble to face.
과연 무사시는 이대로 죽고 마는가? 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Is Musashi going to die like this? Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
무사시 씨? 뭐 봐요?
Musashi? What are you looking at?
구름이오.
Clouds-dasu.
구름?
Clouds?
나, 지금 보이는 저 구름보다도 큰 사내가 되어 보이겠소.
I will be a man with a bigger spirit than that clouds-dasu!
네, 꼭 될 거에요!
Right, you will be!
그 때가 되면 오츠루 씨,
When that time comes, Otsuru,
그 때?
That time?
그 때는... 부드러운 손이오!
When that time comes... what a soft hand-dasu!
정말 얇소!
So thin-dasu!
매끈매끈하오!
How slippery-dasu!
조금 부끄럽지만, 사랑하오.
It's awkward, but I love you-dasu.
오츠루 씨!
Otsuru!
노, 놀랐소. 뭐, 뭐, 뭣이오. 여긴 마치 무예가의 무덤같소!
Shocking... Wh- what is this place-dasu? It is like a grave of Martial Artists!
그 말은, 이 나도...
That means, I also will...
나, 죽기 싫소!
I don't want to die-dasu!
지팡구 제일의 무예가가 되겠소!
I will become the number one Martial Artist of Jipangu-dasu!
이런 일로 꺾일 내가 아니오.
I will not break down by this-dasu.
나, 포기하지 않겠소!
I will not give up-dasu!
더는 싫어...
No more...
이곳이 호조인의 본거지인가.
So this is the stronghold of Hozoin.
호조원
Houzou Temple
과연 막부 정권을 쓰러뜨릴 반역 음모가 있는 것인가.
Are they planning to rebel over the shogunate government?
아이 무예가가 침입자라?
A kid Martial Artist invaded?
호조인 님, 안심해 주십시오. 그 바위굴에 매장하였습니다.
Don't worry, Master Hozoin. We've buried him into a cavern.
호조인
Hozoin
그 놈 혼자였나?
Was he alone?
아니요, 그 녀석의 제자인가 하는 무예가도 있었지만 이게 전혀 말도 하지 않고
No, there was someone who is told to be his pupil, but he didn't talked at all and
천하무적
We are unrivaled
어느 순간 없어지고 말았습니다.
disappeared when we weren't watching.
쥐새끼는 썩 꺼져라!
Get lost, you rat!
그러나 우리 문 밖의 호조인 류를 정탐하러 온 스파이라고 하면...
But what if it's a spy came to observe us Hozoin-ryu?
알려지면 곤란한 비밀은 여기엔 없다.
We do not have any secret that would bring us troble.
그보다도 수련의 장소에 있는 그 산이 황폐화되면 곤란하지.
Aside, if the mountain at our training site is wasted, that will bring us troble.
경비를 확실히 하도록!
Strengthen the defenses!
예!
Got it!
부탁드리오... 누군가 구해 주시오...
Please... somebody save me...
나, 이 곳에선 죽어도 미련 없이 죽지 못하오.
If I die here, I wouldn't be able to die without regrets-dasu.
배고프오... 목도 말랐소...
So hungry... So thirsty too-dasu...
결국 제자도 박정한 사람이오....
The pupil was heartless too after all-dasu...
그래도 이렇게 된다면 스승 따위 멋에 겨워 허세를 부리면 안 됐소...
If I knew I was going to end like this, I shouldn't bluffed about being a master-dasu...
스승님! 무사시 스승님!
Master! Master Musashi!
이걸 잡아 주세요!
Hold this!
와! 하늘의 도움! 코헤이 씨!
Rescue of heaven! Mr. Kohei!
맛있소! 고맙소, 코헤이 씨. 너는 내 생명의 은인이오.
So good! Thank you, Mr. Kohei. I owe you my life-dasu.
무슨 소립니까, 스승님. 이것도 제자가 애쓰는 것입니다.
What are you saying, master? This is also what a pupil does.
자, 좋아하시는 음식인 단고도 드십시오. 여기 있습니다.
Here it is. Your favorite food is dango, right?
맛있소! 정말 맛있소!
So good! It's excellent-dasu!
이건 찹쌀이나 참깨를 뿌린 벌꿀 등으로 개어서 굳힌 비상식으로 영양이 듬뿍 당긴 단고입니다.
These are nutritious dangos made with sticky rice, sesame, honey.
대단한 걸 가지고 있소!
You have awesome things-dasu!
스승님, 진정하세요!
Calm down, master! Calm down!
덕분에 기운이 났소.
Thanks to you, I'm fine now-dasu.
저 절은?
What's that temple?
아마 호조인의 성일 것입니다. 가까이 가지 않는 게...
It must be the castle of Hozoin.
아니오. 멋대로 오버하다가 날 호되게 당하게 한 승병들을 무참히 응징해 주겠소.
No. I will beat those ferocious monks who made me suffer black and blue.
코헤이 씨, 오시오!
Mr. Kohei, follow me-dasu!
누구 있소?
Is anyone there?
누구냐?
Who is it?
어라, 넌 어제 꼬맹이!
You're that brat from yesterday!
잘도 살아 나타났군!
So you live.
미야모토 마을의 무사시는 불사신이오! 시합으로 결판을 내러 왔소!
Musashi from Miyamoto village is immortal-dasu! I am here to settle this with a match-dasu!
흥미롭군.
Interesting.
흥미롭군. 이 호조인에게 시합을 요청하는 것은.
Interesting. So you ask for a match to me, Houjouin.
분수를 모르는 것도 괜찮은 일이지.
Being indiscreet is not a bad thing.
나야말로 지팡구 제일의 무예가를 꿈꾸는 미야모토 마을의 무사시오!
I am Musashi from Miyamoto village, who dreams for the number one Martial Artist of Jipangu!
단도직입적으로 시합을 부탁드리오.
I want to ask you for a match.
다른 유파와의 시합은 금지되어 있지만, 일부러 찾아왔겠구나. 특별히 허가해 주지.
A match against different school is generally prohibited, but I'll let you have one since you came all the way for this.
잔챙이! 상대해 줘라!
You there! Contend with him!
예!
Right!
승부!
Match!
시작하오!
Let's start!
어라?
Huh?
다음!
Next!
졌다!
I lost!
다음!
Next!
졌다!
I lost!
다음!
Next!
에잇! 이깟 한둘은 그저 성가시오! 호조인 님과 승부를 보고 싶소!
These ones are nothing-dasu! I want to have a match against Hozoin-dasu!
칼을 나에게 향하는 것은 좋은 자신감이다.
Some confidence you have, to aim your sword to me.
좋다. 다만 진검승부 이외에는 하지 않겠다. 괜찮나?
Good then. But I do not have a match without a real sword. Are you all right with this?
바라던 바이오!
That's what I wanted-dasu!
무사시! 스승님!
Musashi! ...Master!
걱정하지 마시오!
Do not worry-dasu.
오시오!
Come!
바라던 바이오!
That's what I wanted-dasu!
이 미늘창이야말로 우리 호조인류의 필살무기!
(kamayari: 鎌槍. Spear with curved cross-blades)
This kamayari is our Houjouin family's special weapon!
승부다!
Match starts!
오시오!
Come!
쇠붙이 부분을 계산에 넣지 않았소.
I didn't put the metal part to my calculations-dasu...
보았나? 이게 호조인류 미늘창의 특기. 그것뿐만이 아니라 자르는 기능도 있는 만능 창.
Did you see? This is the specialty of kamayari of us Hozoin-ryu. This spear also can cut. It is capable of anything.
각오해라!
Prepare yourself!
이건 허점을 이용할 틈이 전혀 없소!
I cannot find a way to take advantage of anything-dasu!
끝장이다!
Finishing move!
달아가냐, 꼬맹아!
Are you running away, you brat?!
아니오! 좁은 도장에서는 의의가 막히니까 밖으로 나왔을 뿐이오!
That's not it! I just came out because my spirit was blocked inside the limited space inside Dōjō!
패배를 인정하기 1초 전이군!
One second before you admit your loss!
움직일 수가 없소!
I cannot move-dasu!
이럇, 찌르기다!
Piercing move!
각오해라!
Prepare yourself!
누구냐!
Who did that?!
네이놈.
How dare you...
어? 너는...
Huh? You're...
상대는 아직 소년. 굳이 날뛰어야 한다면 소생이 상대하겠습니다.
The opponent is a boy. If you must be savage, I will content with you.
접시꽃 문장. 제국을 돌아보는 경찰 장관 쥬베 님인가...
Emblem of hollyhock. He must be Jube, the director of police who takes care of whole empire...
쥬베
Jube
한 점 구름도 없는 맑은 눈이다.
He has clear eyes without a cloud.
무언가 보였습니까?
Did you see something?
맑은 하늘입니다.
A clear sky.
그 말을 들으니 안심됩니다.
I am relieved to hear that.
승부를 잊었소, 호조인?
Did you forget the match-dasu, Hozoin?
각오하시오!
Prepare yourself!
잡았소!
I got you!
졌소.
I lost.
어째서오? 지금 승부는 비긴 것이...
Why-dasu? This match is a draw...
아니오. 자랑스러운 창이 끊어진 제가 진 것이오.
No. It is my loss because my spear of pride is cut off.
이후, 정진하겠소이다.
I will devote more, from now on.
저, 정말이오?
Re- really?
해냈다! 해냈소!
I did it! I did it-dasu!
에도토피아의 지팡구 무예 대회에서 새롭게 다시 승부를 보고 싶소.
I want to have a new match against you in Jipangu Martial Arts Competition in Edotopia.
그 바라심은 꼭.
Your wish will certainly be achieved.
그럼.
Then.
조심하시오!
Take care!
감사하오!
Thank you-dasu!
그래도 천하제일로 유명한 쥬베 님이 제자라니, 재미있는 소년이군. 무사시.
You are an interesting boy, Musashi, to claim to have Jube, the unrivaled, as your pupil.
아, 참. 두고 온 것이오.
Ah, right. You forgot something-dasu.
내가 위험했을 때 구해 준 것은 알고 있소.
I know that you saved me when I was in danger-dasu.
아... 그랬습니까. 그 때는 몰두하다가...
Oh... was that so? I was absorbed...
나, 사실은 당신의 스승이 될 만할 자격이 없소. 이해해 주시오.
To tell you the truth, I am not qualified to be your master-dasu. Please understand-dasu.
아니오. 사과할 쪽은 제 쪽입니다. 저는 야규 가(柳生家)의 쥬베라는 자.
No. It's me who have to apologize. I am Jube of Yagyū Family(柳生家).
야규 가? 그 말은 쇼군의 친애를 받는...
Yagyū Family? Then you are directly under the shogun...
쇼군의 명령으로 호조인의 모습을 정탐하기 위해 무사시 님을 이용했습니다.
I used you, Musashi, to spy upon Hozoin, under the order of the shogun.
그런 이유로 사과드립니다.
That's why I must apologize.
아니, 나도 쥬베 씨가 없었다면 뼈가 되어 있었을 것이오. 나야말로 고맙소.
No, instead, if Mr. Jube wasn't there, I would end up as a skeleton-dasu. Thank you-dasu.
무사시 님. 그 마음의 넓이, 이 쥬베가 감탄했습니다!
Mr. Musashi. I am struck with admiration for your wideness of spirit!
또 또 약삭이 빠르기는!
You're all talk again!
그래도 다시 한번 쥬베 님과 승부를 부탁드리오.
But still, I ask you for a match in the future once more-dasu.
그거라면 지팡구 무예대회에서 만납시다.
For that, let's meet in Jipangu Martial Arts Competition.
약속이오.
That's a promise-dasu.
예. 그럼 에도토피아에서.
Right. Then see you at Edotopia.
천하에 유명한 쥬베도 모르며 스승이라 불려 기분이 좋았던 것도 잠깐의 꿈.
Not knowing the world-famous Jube, he had a short but good dream, being called as a master.
그러나, 호조인과 좋은 승부를 한 무사시. 꿈과 희망으로 가슴이 부풀어 에도토피아를 향하고 있었다.
Moreover, Musashi managed to have a good match against Hozoin.
He was heading to Edotopia, heart rosen with dream and hope.
무사시를 기다리는 자는 꽃인가 폭풍인가?
Who will be waiting for Musashi? Wind or storm?
허공의 주머니에 달이
Sometimes the moon jumps over
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
the pocket of the empty sky
큰 소리로 웃으면
Laugh loudly and
내일에는 아침이 와
a morning will come tomorrow
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Don't care too much about losing
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
Keep doing! Go for it!
맨손은 강해
A bare hand is strong
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
That's how life is! Look, a chance
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
follows us wagging its tail!
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
That's how future also is! Look, tomorrow
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
긴 여행을 떠나는 것도 제법 힘든 것이오.
Walking throgh the journey makes me worn out-dasu.
어느덧 꾸벅꾸벅 졸던 나는 이게 무슨, 칼을 도둑맞고 말았소.
I was dozing, and what the?! My swords were stolen.
범인을 찾던 곳에는 바이켄이라는 남자하고 만났지만
I met a man called Baiken while looking for the culprit,
알고 보니 범인은 그 남자의 형제들이었소.
but the culprit was actually his brothers.
다음 이야기! 깨끗하고 가난한 쿠사리가마오
Next story! Clean and Poor Kusarigama
질풍노도의 전력의 격투전이오!
There will be a stormy fight!
다음 이야기
깨끗하고 가난한 쿠사리가마오
기대하세요!
Next Episode
Clean and Poor Kusarigama
Look forwards for it!